Vo, Huynh Quang Nguyen

Github: github.com/vohuynhquangnguyen

ResearchGate: researchgate.net/profile/Huynh-Quang-Nguyen-Vo

Linkedin: linkedin.com/in/quangnguyen-vohuynh

ABOUT ME

I am an engineering and science enthusiast having the core values of agility, responsibility, and teamwork. To fulfill my dream of becoming an influential researcher in my field, I always push myself out of my comfort zone to achieve my goals. During my free time, I devote wholeheartedly to my lifelong passions: liberal arts, and language.

I can offer my solid understanding of Semiconductor Devices, Optical Metrology, Computer Vision, and Data Science thanks to the experiences I accumulated from my work placements and my studies. Besides, I possess an excellent eye for detail, a hard-working and responsible personality, and project management skills. These skills and experience should make me an ideal candidate for positions related to Semiconductor Design and Manufacturing, Data Analytics, and Machine Learning Operations.

EDUCATION

Helsinki Metropolia University of Applied Sciences

Helsinki, Finland

September 2014 - April 2018

Email: quangnguyenvohuynh@gmail.com

Mobile: +84 (0) 396 957 043

 $Degree\ in\ Electronics\ (B.\, Tech.)$

- o Graduated with Honors: GPA 4.6/5.0
- Awards: Tutor of the Year (2015-2016): for utmost dedication to the well-being and smooth integration of international exchange students.
- Learning Paths: Power Electronics, Embedded Systems, Digital Systems Design, Cognitive Systems.

Aalto University

Espoo, Finland

 $Degree\ in\ Translational\ Engineering\ (M.Sc.)$

September 2018 - December 2020

- o Graduated with Honors: GPA 4.2/5.0
- $\circ\,$ Awards: Dean's List 2019-2020.
- o Majors: Smart Systems Integration; Measuring Technology (focused on Photonics and Optical Metrology).
- o Minor: Data Science.

SKILLS SUMMARY

- Languages: English (certified C2 level).
- **Programming**: Python (incl. scikit-learn, Pandas, Numpy, TensorFlow, and OpenCV); MATLAB; LabVIEW; Arduino; LaTEX.
- Knowledge: Computer Vision; Data Science; Semiconductor Engineering; Optical Metrology; Power Electronics.
- Soft-skills: Project Management; Event Planning and Coordination; Public Speaking.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Intel Products Vietnam (VNAT)

Saigon Hi-Tech Park, Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam

Process and Equipment Engineer - Machine Learning Developer

April 2021 - now

- Machine Learning & Deep Learning Development: Lead several in-house projects at VNAT about applied deep learning technology in product inspection in downstream operations.
- o **Technical Competency Improvement**: Curate tutorials and sharing sessions on computer vision concepts to support the Image Analytics Center of Excellence (based at Intel Ireland); Coach Python programming and machine learning methods as a mentor of Intel AI Everywhere Community. Both the Center of Excellence and the Community are focusing on democratizing AI-related subjects throughout the entire corporation.
- Employee Integration: Manage communications as well as organize and coordinate events/activities for NextGen Vietnam a regional subsidiary of Intel NextGen Initiative which focuses on integrating and developing employees' competency.

First Solar Vietnam

Dong Nam Industrial Park, Cu Chi, Vietnam November 2020 - March 2021

Manufacturing Engineer Trainee

- **Project**: Established a standardized electroluminescence image database for fault detection and diagnosis in the laser scribing process for thin-film solar panels. The project was completed successfully, and its results were used as a whitepaper for troubleshooting tasks in laser scribing. Additionally, the process monitoring software developed during the project was verified and is currently applied to all of First Solar's factories.
- **Technical Sharing**: Organized several technical sharing sessions about laser physics and optics in engineering. These sessions were well applauded by the attendees "[the team] have found a lot of knowledge useful that [the team] didn't get at college and university", as quoted by Mr. Tam Huynh (Senior Manufacturing Engineer).

SolarBK

Research and Development Associate - Thesis Worker

Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam July 2020 - September 2020

- **Project (Master Thesis)**: Developed an AI-based method to evaluate silicon photovoltaic cells' reliability for quality assurance purposes. After 30.09.2020, RMIT University Vietnam became the new sponsor of this project. The project was completed successfully, and the corresponding thesis was published in January 2021.
- Fundraising: Assisted in writing funding applications for two joint-venture projects between SolarBK and their collaborators that were Synergict UK and Arup UK, respectively. These applications were submitted to the Energy Catalyst Round 8, which was a funding competition organized by Innovate UK.

Aalto University – Metrology Research Institute

Espoo, Finland

Research Assistant

March 2019 - December 2019

- Research: Assisted the research team in a project that was funded by EMPIR about the characterization and standardization of solar cell performance. The project was completed successfully, and the results were published as a conference paper for the Optics in Engineering Symposium (OIE2019) in the Optical Review journal, Springer.
- Miscellaneous: Assisted in the measurement, evaluation, and calibration of optical spectrometry devices.

Noiseless Acoustics Oy

Helsinki, Finland

Electronics Manufacturing and Test Engineer

March 2018 - November 2018

- Analysis: Developed testing modules for the NL Camera product and conducted reliability analysis using the Failure Mode Effect Analysis (FMEA) methodology. The modules and analysis were successfully implemented and contributed to the advancement of the product's reliability.
- Miscellaneous: Implemented the Inventory Management System that significantly eased the tracking of products in multiple stages (in-progress, finished, reworked, etc.) and component stocks; Assisted in the production of NL Camera that enabled the company to achieve its targeted quota to meet the increasing market.

MDS Finland Oy

Helsinki, Finland

Occupational Health Research and Development Engineer - Thesis Worker

May 2017 - October 2017

- **Project (Bachelor Thesis)**: Developed a system for Machine Safety for Construction Industry. The thesis was completed successfully and served as a precursor to creating one of MDS' first products.
- Analysis: Conducted a study about the Safety of Excavators in the Finnish Construction Industry that helped the company to realize there was a potential market for safety systems in this industry.

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

Aalto University

Espoo, Finland

Teaching and Exercises Assistant

March 2019 - June 2019

- o **Training**: Pedagogy Training for Teaching Assistant.
- o Courses: ELEC-E5710 Sensors and Measurement Methods by Dr. Petri Kärhä.

Aalto University

Espoo, Finland

Master Thesis Advisor

Jan 2022 - June 2022

o Master Thesis: Crown-of-Thorns Starfish (COTS) detection by state-of-the-art YOLOv5, authored by Phuong Truong.

RMIT University Vietnam Visiting Lecturer

Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam

Jan~2023

o Guest Lecture: Optics/Optoelectronic Applications in Reality.

PUBLICATIONS

- Case study: Utilising of Deep Learning Models for Fault Detection and Diagnosis of Photovoltaic Modules to Improve Solar Energy Constructions' O&M Activities Quality (Book Chapter): Khuong Nguyen-Vinh, Huynh Vo, Khoa Nguyen-Minh, Minh Hoang. Information Systems Research in Vietnam (Second Volume); Springer; 2023. Currently under peer review. Link to the book is here.
- Measurement setup for differential spectral responsivity of solar cells (Article): Petri Kärhä, Hans Baumgartner, Janne Askola, Kasperi Kylmänen, Benjamin Oksanen, Kinza Maham, Huynh Vo & Erkki Ikonen. Optical Review, Volume 27, p. 195–204; Springer; 2020. Link to the article is here.
- Safety System in Construction Industry: A protection system preventing fatal injuries by excavators in construction sites (Thesis): Huynh Vo. Open Repository of the Universities of Applied Sciences; 2018. Link to the thesis is here.
- Realization and Verification of Deep Learning models for Fault Detection and Diagnosis of Photovoltaic Modules (Thesis): Huynh Vo. Aalto Learning Center; 2020. Link to the thesis is here.

Intelligent Inspection and Automatic Disposition System

Software Architect

Intel Products Vietnam September 2021 - now

• **Description**: The project was about the development of a decentralized intelligent inspection system for material handling processes at downstream operations.

Applied Deep Learning on Inspection in Reel Packaging

Software Architect

Intel Products Vietnam August 2021 - August 2022

o **Description**: The project was about the development of an automated inspection program that is capable of detecting whether packaging issues (e.g., out-of-pocket) occur and prompting technicians/operators to take corrective actions with haste during the entire reel packaging process. The project was completed successfully, and was documented as a process-of-record.

Modelling and Control Methods in Renewable Energy Systems

Aalto University, Finland January 2020 - June 2020

Project Manager

• **Description**: The project was about the development of a feasible algorithm that allows the photovoltaic system to generate maximum power to apply short-haul distance electric vehicle charging stations. The project was funded by Fortum Oy, one of the largest energy companies in Finland.

Life Cycle Assessment of the Samsung Galaxy Watch

Project Manager

Aalto University, Finland September 2019 - December 2019

• **Description**: The project was about the implementation of the life cycle assessment (LCA) of the recently introduced Samsung Galaxy Watch. The project aimed to raise more self-awareness about the environmental impacts of this product.

• International Sensor Development Project • Sensor System Designer

Helsinki Metropolia University of Applied Sciences, Finland
October 2016 - February 2017

• **Description**: This was a collaboration project between Helsinki Metropolia University of Applied Sciences (Finland) UAS and Osnabrück Hochschule (Germany) to develop an indoor quality supervisor system. The system aimed to be capable of detecting air quality, and sending and visualizing measured data to users via an in-house mobile application; the system also included an integrated warning functionality that could only be triggered when the measured levels exceed threshold ones. The project was completed successfully, and plans were laid down to improve the system further using the new Bosch sensor introduced in Q2'17.

RECOMMENDATIONS

- Matti Fisher, D.Sc.(Tech.): Principal Lecturer of Helsinki Metropolia University of Applied Sciences
 - o **Mobile**: +358 505 279 893
 - $\circ\,$ Email: matti.fischer@metropolia.fi
- Petri Kärhä, D.Sc.(Tech.): Docent of Aalto University
 - Mobile: +358 505 968 469
 Email: petri.karha@aalto.fi
- Simo Särkkä, D.Sc.(Tech.): Associated Professor at Aalto University
 - \circ Mobile: +358 505 124 393 \circ Email: simo.sarkka@aalto.fi
- Vinh-Khuong Nguyen, Doctoral Candidate: Associated Lecturer of RMIT University
 - \circ **Mobile**: +358 505 124 393
 - o Email: khuong.nguyenvinh@rmit.edu.vn
- Phuong-Tuan Nguyen Phan, B.Tech.: Senior Manufacturing Engineer of First Solar Vietnam
 - $\circ \ \mathbf{Email} : \ ngocphuongtuan.nguyen@firstsolar.com$
 - $\circ \ \, \textbf{Mobile:} \, \, +84 \,\, 935 \,\, 207 \,\, 422 \,\,$
- Thanh Hai Nguyen, M.Sc. (Tech.): Manufacturing Engineer Manager of First Solar Vietnam
 - o Email: nguyenthanh.hai@firstsolar.com
- Harley Fagan, B.Tech.: Engineering Manager
 - \circ $\mathbf{Email}:$ harley.l.fagan@intel.com
 - \circ **Mobile**: +1 4803 691 547